Jordan Craig Hornblow

Timaru, Canterbury, New Zealand

Email: jordan@jch254.com

Website: linktr.ee/jch254 | linkedin.com/in/jch254

I'm Jordan, a software engineer interested in music. I was born in New Zealand where I spent the first 23 years of my life. I moved to Melbourne, Australia in 2014 after enjoying thousands of earthquakes in Christchurch and deciding a broken city was not for me at the time. After eight years living life in Melbourne I took the opportunity to relocate to Austin, TX mid 2022 for work. I am currently living and working remotely back in New Zealand after relocating home in early 2024.

I love that one can never know too much about technology. There is always an opportunity to continue expanding and applying my knowledge base. This concept of continual improvement is one I have found to be common among all my interests.

I enjoy working across all aspects of product development. I believe that a deeper understanding of the stack allows one to architect higher quality/more robust solutions and diagnose/solve bugs/issues more efficiently. I revel in building applications/systems from the ground up as well as maintaining and enhancing pre-existing systems.

Work Experience

Apr 2024 - Present

LawVu - Remote, New Zealand - Senior Software Engineer L2

• I am currently working as a Senior Software Engineer L2 at LawVu in New Zealand.

Jun 2022 - Mar 2023

Mr Yum - Austin, TX, US - US Integrations (Principal Engineer)

I moved to Austin, TX to focus on integrations with Mr Yum's US based partners.
 See below for further info:

Apr 2020 - Jun 2022 Mr Yum - Melbourne, Australia - Head of Integrations (Principal Engineer)

- I joined Mr Yum as an early engineer and contributed significantly to the core platform's development. My primary focus revolved around forging seamless integrations with third-party partners (we were served almost every flavor of API). Working alongside a skilled team of developers, I utilized diverse technologies like TypeScript, React, Node.js, NestJS, GraphQL, Terraform, and AWS to power multiple products.
- One of my key contributions involved starting the process of strategically dismantling our monolithic system into more agile, focused services. This began by modularizing the integrations service, paving the way for increased scalability and agility.
- During my tenure, Mr Yum achieved a major milestone by securing Australia's third-largest Series A funding round in 2021, amounting to an impressive \$65 million USD.

Dec 2016 - Jul 2020

APositive - Melbourne, Australia - Senior Full Stack Developer

I worked as a Senior Full Stack Developer at APositive Workforce Finance in Melbourne. I
worked on multiple projects powered by various technologies including React, Node.js, Terraform
and AWS. APay is one product I created at APositive.

See below:

May 2014 - Oct 2016

Xero - Melbourne, Australia - Developer

- I worked in several teams across a number of projects during my time at Xero in Melbourne.
 Whenever approached about joining a new project, I jumped at the chance for a new challenge and the opportunity to grow myself. I worked remotely during my last eight months of employment.
- I worked on the core Xero web app during my first year at Xero. I was involved in the development and release of features such as fixed assets, quotes, two-factor authentication and batch provisioning. I also helped out with bug-fixing and maintenance etc. whenever required.
- I worked on the Xero TaxTouch iOS app during my last eighteen months at Xero. I was a key
 player throughout all aspects of the project from initial designs to development to release and
 production support. TaxTouch was an exciting project working with internal and external teams
 across different time zones. I gained invaluable experience going through the process of building
 an iOS app from conception to release and working with many new technologies.

Mar 2012 - Mar 2014

Telogis - Christchurch, NZ - Software Engineer

- I worked at Telogis as a Software Engineer on the enterprise fleet management SaaS 'Telogis
 Fleet'. The majority of my work was in .NET, Javascript and PostgreSQL using an agile
 development process (Kanban) with thorough testing. My role included a leadership aspect which
 involved mentoring new staff members on my team, delegating tasks and reviewing
 code/performance.
- I worked on new feature design/implementation, general bug-fixing and optimization of the Telogis Fleet backend, along with interprocess communication between many of Telogis' server side processes.
- I also worked on the Telogis Fleet UI, redesigning and re-implementing interfaces using the Javascript framework Ext JS. I also created several custom Ext JS components which are used in other Telogis products.
- In July/August 2013, I spent five weeks at another Telogis development office in Austin, Texas, USA on a developer exchange. The work was at a lower level of the Telogis stack than my usual role and included working on Telogis' server side processes. These processes received raw UDP packets containing GPS and diagnostic information from vehicles and converted them into a useful and standardized format. I also created an integral monitoring service for these processes.

Feb 2011 - Mar 2014

Kiwi Development - Christchurch, NZ - Founder/Software Engineer

- I founded Kiwi Development to further my skills in software and web development and to learn the
 foundations of running a business. Kiwi Development was accepted into the Microsoft Bizspark
 program for young tech startups. I undertook both web and software development work for
 multiple clients using .NET, Ruby on Rails and Javascript.
- One major client was 'The Inzone Experience' where I was in charge of their systems. This role
 involved managing several Windows servers running .NET web applications with SQL Server
 databases. I also maintained and enhanced their main web application which runs on hundreds of
 kiosks throughout NZ to be more efficient and reliable.

- I worked at Canterbury University as a tutor for first year computer science and software engineering papers which teach programming skills in Python. I ran labs of up to 50 students. This role involved explanation and understanding of core computer science and software engineering concepts, helping students out when needed and essential people skills.
- I also worked as a tutor for the Pacific Academic Solutions & Success programme, where I tutored Pacific students in computer science and software engineering papers.

Nov 2010 - Feb 2011

HITLab NZ - Christchurch, NZ - Research Intern

• I was awarded a University of Canterbury Summer Scholarship which allowed me to work in the HITLab as a research intern on a project titled "Exploring the use of Mobile Augmented Reality for Navigation". My main responsibility within this project was running user experiments, recording and analyzing the data. I also had to learn Android programming skills, and acquire an understanding of mobile augmented reality systems.

Education

2009 - 2011

University of Canterbury - Christchurch, NZ - BSc (Computer Science)

• I worked on several projects in Java, C, C++, Python and Android. I was part of a year-long, six person software engineering group project developing an Audience Response System. This system allowed university lecturers to 'ask' a class full of students questions and collect/visualize responses from these students in real time. This was done via a Java based web application which lecturers used to 'ask' questions, and an Android application for students to respond to these questions.

2004 - 2008

Timaru Boys High School - Timaru, NZ

Achievements/awards

- University of Canterbury Summer Scholarship 2010-2011
- Member of the Golden Key International Honour Society 2009 onwards
- University of Canterbury College of Engineering Computer Science Scholarship 2009
- NCEA Levels 1, 2, and 3/NZ University Entrance

Hobbies

- Music (listening and playing/producing)
- Vinyl collecting
- Open source software

References

Andrei Miulescu Co-founder/CTO - Mr Yum me@andreimc.com (+61) 406 569 141 Errol Katz
Co-founder/Director - APositive
errol.katz@apositive.com.au
(+61) 438 377 655